A Guide to the Wood Blocks and Prints of Julius J. Lankes, 1923 and 1951
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Wood Blocks and Prints of Julius J. Lankes, 1923 and 1951
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10164-h
This collection consists of thirty items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the Library on January 9, 1987 by J.B. Lankes of Hampton, Virginia and Mrs. Madeleine deBarthe Schuermann of Temple Hill, Maryland in memory of his father, J.J. Lankes.
Scope and Content Information
The thirty items, 1923 and 1951, in this collection pertain chiefly to J.J. Lankes' illustration of Marvin Neel's Weather Sayings and, to a lesser extent, Robert Frost's "The star-splitter" ( The Century Magazine, September 1923). Included are thirteen woodblocks, cut in end grain maple by J.J. Lankes between April and June 1951, with thirteen accompanying reference prints, used to illustrate Weather Sayings. There are also four reference prints made from woodblocks used to illustrate "The star- splitter."
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically by series.
Contents List
- Weather Sayings
  - Wood block 1137 1951 April 30
    January--Half moon, barn. Accompanied by reference print.
  - Wood block 1138 1951 May 1
    February -- Brook. Accompanied by reference print.
  - Wood block 1141 1951 May 4
    August -- Sunset. Accompanied by reference print.
  - Wook block 1142 1951 May 5
    June -- Windy Hilltop. Accompanied by reference print.
  - Wood block 1143 1951 May 11
    September -- Rain in Vermont. Accompanied by reference print.
  - Wood block 1144 1951 May 14
    March -- Wind. Accompanied by reference print.
  - Wood block 1145 1951 May 17
    November -- "Frost Poem." Accompanied by reference print.
  - Wood block 1147 1951 May 24
    Frontispiece -- Skating II. Accompanied by reference print.
  - Wood block 1149 1951 May 31
    May -- Orchard, church, clouds II. Accompanied by reference print.
  - Wood block 1150 1951 June 12
    July -- Hay V. Accompanied by reference print.
  - Wood block 1151 1951 June 14
    April -- Plowing. Accompanied by reference print.
  - Wood block 1153 1951 June 26
    December -- Getting Xmas Tree II. Accompanied by reference print.
  - Wood block 1154 1951 June 27
    October -- Cornfield II. Accompanied by reference print.
- "The Star-Splitter"
  - Print from wood block 234 1923 May 20
    Title Page -- Whitaker's Farm, NJ.
  - Print from wood block 235 1923 May 23
    Dawn I -- Lightning wrong.
  - Print from wood block 237 1923 May 25
    Headpiece. Printed together with wood block 239.
  - Print from wood block 239 1923 June 1
    Headpiece Top. Printed together with wood block 237.
  - Print from wood block 240 1923 June 2
    Farmhouse.